<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Zeid Ombotimbe</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Zeid Ombotimbe</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2025 Zeid Ombotimbe. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 10:00:00 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Higher-Order Thinking: How Scala&#39;s Functional Abstractions Simplify Complex Logic</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/higher-order-thinking-scala/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 10:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/higher-order-thinking-scala/</guid>
      <description>I remember staring at a Python script at 2 AM, tracing through nested loops and conditional logic that processed user analytics data.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scala Options: Stop Fearing Null, Start Loving Safety</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/scala-options/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/scala-options/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;re coming from Python, you&amp;rsquo;re probably used to this pattern:&#xA;user = get_user(user_id) if user is not None: process_user(user) else: print(&amp;#34;User not found&amp;#34;) And you&amp;rsquo;re probably also used to this happening in production:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building My First Data Pipeline</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/my-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Apr 2025 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/my-first-post/</guid>
      <description>Just deployed my first end-to-end pipeline using Airflow, S3, and Redshift. Here’s what I learned about idempotency and backfilling&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mastering SQL Subqueries: Your Secret Weapon for Smarter Queries</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/sql-subqueries/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/sql-subqueries/</guid>
      <description>SQL queries can feel like magic when you need exactly the right answer from your data.&#xA;And subqueries? They’re the quiet superpower behind some of the cleanest, most powerful SQL you’ll ever write.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Linear Regression vs Logistic Regression - Understanding the Differences</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/linear-regression-logistic-regression/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/linear-regression-logistic-regression/</guid>
      <description>Data analysis often uses two tools: linear regression and logistic regression. They sound alike, but they answer different questions. This article breaks down their differences with clear examples and the math behind them, so you can choose the right one for your data.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scala for Angry Beginners: From Frustration to Functional</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/scala-for-angry-beginners/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/scala-for-angry-beginners/</guid>
      <description>Let me guess: you&amp;rsquo;re a perfectly competent Python developer who&amp;rsquo;s been told you need to learn Scala. Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s for a new job, maybe it&amp;rsquo;s for that Spark project, or maybe you just heard it pays well.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SQL Joins: The Ultimate Guide to Not Breaking Your Database</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/sql-joins/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/sql-joins/</guid>
      <description>Hey there, SQL enthusiast! Ever felt the thrill of joining two tables and getting exactly the data you wanted? Or the panic when your query runs for hours and your database starts smoking?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Running a Coding Boot Camp Taught Me About Programming</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/running-a-bootcamp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/running-a-bootcamp/</guid>
      <description>I’ve always loved coding. As a data nerd, I spend my days tinkering with Python scripts and digging into datasets. So when I got the chance to run a six-week coding boot camp for beginners in early 2022, I was thrilled.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
